Can't stop laughing. Two minutes late.
>> We've done this before.
>> Get to see you guys twice the same day.
>> Actually going to get them three times
tonight, too.
>> We'll get them tonight.
>> Oh, you get to do that when you got two
of these pigs, don't you?
>> Well, keep them coming.
>> Okay. Yes, sir.
>> That's it. Watch it. I fell off this
thing the other night.
>> Fell in that hole.
>> I've been I've been scarred me scarred
mentally for life.
>> He actually showed good contact balance.
He didn't fall.
>> Hey, I tell you, it's so bad. I dreamed
about it and then I drove my car in a
different way to not get close to this
today.
>> Scared me so bad.
>> Um, right before we get started, we just
want to welcome Malachi's family and
girlfriend here. Malik, why don't you
introduce them?
>> Uh, so that's my mom, uh, Ty, my
girlfriend, Jasmine, and my dad, Randy.
>> All right.
>> Welcome to Texas,
>> Dallas.
>> All right, Calvin, you want to start us
out?
>> Sure. Calvin Watkins, Dallas Morning
News. A lot of people have said you have
a lot of different pass rush moves and
somebody so young, how did you develop
your pass rush moves? Obviously, teams
like it because look what they did for
you,
>> right? Uh, true. When I got first to
college, I really didn't have any pass
ski abilities or skills, I'd say, that I
knew about yet. So, like when I got
there, just looking up to the older
guys, I say, uh, Traymond Morris, Brash,
we called him drop. Uh, just learning
from him, uh, he was very flexible and
like he would go do different moves and
so just watching him at practice and
then recreating him. I say that's what
that's how my arsenal kind of started
growing. And then different coaches as
well. Shotty, did the draft process, how
much did the coaches talk to you about
the moves that he's been able to do so
far?
>> Yeah. Well, again, we had a little
inside information with coach Brim. Uh,
but again, the film when you watch it,
it just it's very apparent. The ability
to bend, the ability to turn his toe,
the ability to accelerate off of
different angles. And I think I said it
last night when we were talking about
you, what we love about him is he
doesn't just get the quarterback, he
gets the ball. And uh that's a big
emphasis for us this year getting uh
getting back right in the giveaway
takeaway margin.
>> Todd Archer with ESPN. Where does that
come from? What coach was just talking
about that it's just not the
quarterback, it's about the ball. Was
that something you taught early or
something? It was just kind of you you
figured out that okay, that's more
important,
>> right? Yes. So uh we were taught early
at UCF just keying the ball, getting the
ball back to our offense. That's the
main part of defense really. And so if
we can do it quicker than four down or
four plays, then that's great. So our
coach just emphasized uh run reach.
That's what he would call it.
>> And what's it like to have coach Brim
here? What was it like to see him here
today?
>> Oh, it was a blessing. Uh seeing him at
UCF and then also seeing him get uh a
better job, I say, for him. Um I was
happy for him. And then just seeing him,
he was also happy for me just being
here. Sh. I love coach Brim.
>> John with the athletic. What's this
experience been like today for you?
>> Oh, it's been great. Shoot. Got in here
this morning. Uh, tried on some cowboy
boots. I got to meet some of the staff.
So, yeah, it's been great. Great
experience. First time ever even putting
on cowboy boots since I was younger.
>> And then when you got drafted by the
Cowboys, are you immediately thinking
like, man, this is a great fit for me
for what they do defensively, or are you
just thinking, hey, I'm just happy some
team took me? No,
>> I'm definitely thinking it's a great fit
for me defensively. uh that three four
scheme and also just like they said
bringing in coach Brim uh a familiar
face. So already just being familiar
with his face and he's been telling me
great things about uh the staff here.
I'm ready to I'm ready to get to it.
>> Nick Harris fourstar telegram throughout
the draft process you just continued to
ascend. When in the process did you feel
like hey I could be a firstrounder and
then you finally hear your name called
in the first round last night. Just your
emotions through all that.
>> Right. Um, like probably during that
process of just working out at EXOS,
like I don't I know they don't have no
say, but they were just saying like,
"Oh, dang. He's explosive." And I was
kind of surprising them at Exos just
with my explosive ability. Like when I
got there, they probably they didn't
really know what I could do. So when I
got there and showcased it and then got
to the uh NFL combine and got to
actually showcase those abilities, I
feel like that's when it grew.
>> When you left UCF and started the draft
process, where did you think you would
maybe be drafted, best case scenario?
Right. Maybe like third, fourth round
just like based off based off tape I
say. Um but like like I said I was kind
of like a lower like my name was kind of
just on the rise at the end of the
season I say.
>> Would allow your name to blow up you
think?
>> Right. Uh just different things. Social
media is weird. So
>> yes it is.
>> Right. So shoot what's on somebody's
engagement might not be on somebody
else's. So, I say that and just like
also a good uh showing at the All-Star
game here at the East West Shrine. Uh I
had some good practices.
>> Tom,
>> Tommy, Stylescowboys.com. Mala, you
mentioned being here for that East West
Shrine game. What did you make of
Frisco, the Star, and now that you get
to call it home?
>> Oh, yeah. Sh. I love the city of Frisco.
Uh great things to do, great
restaurants. Sh one of my favorite
Firebirds. Shoo. I love them.
So, yeah. Um, and then the Star, like I
was staying at the Beexley, so it's
right next to the Star. So, I was kind
of used familiar with this area. I had
uh tried something to eat over there.
Um, and then shoot, just like the East
West Shrine, what I was trying to do,
just showcase like my abilities again,
just grow my name.
>> We started talking to Christian Parker
earlier today. What have your
conversations been like with him early
and how does he see you fitting into his
defense?
>> Right. Um, sure. He said just go get
that quarterback. Literally like when I
met him today, he was just like, "Are
you ready to go get the quarterback?"
I'm like, "Yes, sir."
>> Has you met him prior to today?
>> Uh, no sir. I I think so. At the formal
Oh, yeah. Formal.
>> Mhm.
>> Garrett.
>> Garrett Podell, CBS Sports. Malachi,
what do you envision kind of the role
that you can provide for Dallas in your
first year here?
>> Right. Somebody that's just going to be
productive. Uh, someone that's going to
go out there, give it his all. like I'm
just ready to come in and be productive.
Like I said,
>> Brian, what did you think when you saw
him on tape and you know there were
stories about texting pictures of
prospects? Was he one of the guys that
you were really on Will Mccclelay about?
Yeah, I think, you know, he's a guy
we've been talking about for the past
three or four weeks and um the pass rush
stuff is is very evident, but when you
watch him with his speed and ability to
chase down edges and chase quarterbacks
and there's a play against Kansas State
where a very athletic quarterback is
scrambling, you remember the play, he
spins out and he keeps going and he's
chasing them and it's it's crazy back
and forth, but he never gives up and
ends up chasing him down. And in this
division, we've got really athletic
quarterbacks and um they're going to
want to try to put our edge pieces in
conflict with run read options. And uh
my money's on this guy.
>> Scott,
>> Scott with the AP. Stephen, you guys
have used that sort of second pick
whether it's in the first round or the
second round on edge rushers. Pretty
long a while back. You moved up to get
Demarcus early in the second round. How
do you view that position and and going
into the draft and and you know with
with what you feel like the needs are
with this bunch? How that fits in? Yeah,
I think uh you know something that's
always resonated with me and it doesn't
matter who your head coach is or your
defensive coordinator are you can't have
enough and uh certainly that's why we're
always uh looking uh not only to have
quality there and that's why we use high
picks uh but also uh the quantity the
numbers I think are real important if
you want to win games in the fourth
quarter you don't want two guys out
there who've had to play every snap and
they're not fresh at the end when you're
trying to close a game out. As we all
know from following this league, a lot
of these games are won uh in the fourth
quarter. And uh I just think it's so
important in terms of the resources that
we have uh to really uh certainly uh you
know really emphasize uh that particular
position and I think that's why you
always see us doing that. Obviously, uh
when they do really well, uh you know,
it's hard to keep them all because they
really do get paid well, uh you know, if
their first four or five years, uh they
do really well, then at some point you
got to kind of keep them coming because
you, you know, you only have so many cap
resources in terms of the money and
certainly hitting on players in the
draft is a big part of what we're about
in terms of needing to have success
there with the edge rushers. Sydney
>> Sydney Staples, TG10 Sports. Malachi,
what is your earliest football memory?
>> Um, shoot
probably like five years old, just
scoring a lot of touchdowns when I was a
running back. So, yeah, I say that that
was my earliest memory.
>> Patrick,
>> hey, Mal. Patrick Walker, Dallas
Cowboys.com. This is a two-part
question. First part is to you, the
other part is to the front office
general. I know your answer shines
because you love the kid. Um, you've
already made history for the Cowboys.
I'm not sure if you know, but you're the
first player out of UCF they've ever
selected in the first round. What does
that mean to you, and does that add any
extra motivation to try to be great for
this organization?
>> Right. Sure. It means a lot just to be
the first of anything. Um, it's like a a
standard now to be set, I say, uh, for
UCF, like kind of you could go to UCF
and be a first round pick on defense.
So, that and then what was the other
part? No, I mean because that puts you
in the same area as Dante Co Pepper.
What is it? I mean, does it add any
motivation beyond what you already have
to be great for this organization? Oh,
yeah. Definitely
first round pick,
>> right? Definitely. Just shoot
representing my family in the right way
and also UCF in the right way. Like I
want to just put on a good name for uh
UCF. So like when coaches and scouts are
going back there, they'll be like,
"Let's go check out UCF. I heard they
have a a talented defensive or offensive
uh guy." So I say that. And for Jared
and Stephen, what was it about Malachi
that made you break rank on something
you've never done before, but you're
looking at this young man, you're
looking at the UCF program and you're
saying, "We're going to do something for
the first time here and making him our
first round pickup." UCF,
>> no, I think it's just going back to what
I just said. I mean, obviously, you turn
on his tape and it speaks volumes as to
the type of player he is, uh, the
production he had there, the way he
evolved, uh, you know, the character was
just outstanding. I mean, I really look
up uh to these men who stay, you know,
with the schools who gave him their
first opportunity. And certainly, he had
opportunities probably to take more
money and go to a bigger school. And uh,
you know, he felt like uh UCF had given
him a uh the opportunity and he wanted
to give back and uh you know, that
speaks volumes to me about his character
as a man and uh uh but then again, you
turn on the tape obviously we followed
him through his workouts. We have a ca a
coach on staff obviously who knows him
really well and I think you put all that
together and we felt very comfortable
making him a first round pick.
>> Hey Malachi Adam Roso Spectrum News um
working at EXOS with Brandon Tucker,
Donis Armstrong, those guys. How do you
think that helped you in the pre-draft
process and maybe kind of lay a
foundation for for the NFL?
>> Right. It helped me a lot um just
working out with those guys and also
just the guys that I was working out
with. Uh it was kind of like we created
a brotherhood. So it wasn't like we're
just showing up and we have to do this.
No, we wanted to come in and work. And
that's what makes things better. It
makes you just be able to actually
compete with like your brother. So I say
they definitely helped a lot just
bringing that brotherhood uh atmosphere
in
>> who are you off the field?
>> I'm a chill guy. I'm simple. I just play
the game, cook. I might get into
golfing. Uh I've been hearing a a lot of
stuff. Uh, Quinnon Williams.
>> Quinnon? Yeah.
>> He's probably on the golf course right
now.
>> What do you cook?
>> Seafood. I'm a seafood guy.
>> Yeah.
>> There's obviously a big spotlight on on
this franchise. Why do you feel like
you're ready to deal with that
spotlight?
>> Right. Sh. I feel like I'm ready just
because
I wouldn't be putting this opportunity
if I wasn't. I believe like God makes no
mistakes and I believe that I'm here.
Like it wasn't a mistake. I'm here and
I'm ready for it. Pat
>> Pat Dhoni NBC DFW Malachi you're one of
two
>> draft picks that are defensive players
in this first round. You'll be tied to
Caleb DS forever now.
>> Right.
>> What what do you know about him? How
excited are you to play with him? Tell
me a little about that.
>> Right. I know a little bit about him. Uh
just a great safety out of Ohio State.
Uh comes down great tackler
defense. Like just watching his film, he
does a lot of great things and I'm just
excited to get on the field and play
with him. Like I've been hearing like
also other of like his former teammates
at Ohio State just talk about him and
like interviews just how he's a great
great person on and off the field.
>> And then Jerry, you've been doing this
for a while and had a lot of first round
picks walk through the door. Does it
ever get old seeing these guys walk in
for the first time in the wide eyes of
being a draft pick and having this day
and this moment?
>> Not at all. I I can appreciate uh uh I
can remember like yesterday sitting with
Russell Maryland and uh from Miami and
thought combination of things. I had
such respect for him because of uh what
he was doing and yet at the same time I
envied him because of the opportunity he
had and what he was going to get to do.
And so, uh, it's a, uh, it's a real, in
my mind, it's just, uh, you get to hang
out, if you will, with, uh, guys that
for this period of time in their life,
they're getting to do it. In his case,
we've worked real hard, uh, to get an
interior of our defensive line and get
that interior flanged up. Uh, when I
look back comparing, this is me. This is
totally me. But I look back and say now,
how have we gone this long? And we
hadn't gotten uh to where we really want
to go. And look at the consistent. I
move I have to get away from my mirror
because I'm pretty consistently been
around here the whole time as well. But
I felt strongly
uh and have for the last really several
months that we needed to change what we
were doing and uh change the approach we
have to the size or to the impact we
have in the middle. But then uh also
what if you have the opportunity, you
don't know if he's going to get it to
not only get someone that is apt at
putting pressure putting the pressure
out there, but also he calls it the toe,
he calls it a different shot for it, but
also right at the end can bite at the
same time they're putting the pressure.
And of all the guys that we looked at in
the draft, this is the one that stood
out the most. uh uh a couple of them up
there that uh uh or at least one that
might have uh looked stronger and more
physical at the point of attack. Uh but
we we had a knockdown dragout for about
20 minutes before the draft. what he's
bringing to the table if we've done the
other things right is the thing that we
need to have to put the icing on the
cake if it works out.
>> Got it. M Stephen mentioned it earlier
staying at UCF in the portal era it's
era it seems like that's going to be
less and less frequent somebody playing
four years at one school. How much did
teams ask about that in the draft
process?
>> Right. Shoot. I feel like every team
asked
>> just to like cuz they said like you said
it's rare in this era. So they were just
asking like why I stayed, what was my
reason and basically just gave him the
same answer like just growing into that
leadership captain role with the younger
guys.
>> Did you feel like that was a pretty good
selling point for you and in talking to
teams?
>> Yes, sir. Definitely. Cuz like that like
that was the question I probably got
asked every single time like besides
like all the X's and O's. So definitely
>> Cal,
>> your coach left I think maybe a month
into you after you committed to UCF. So
how hard was that to say
>> I committed to the school and the guys
recruited me. He he bounces. So Right.
>> How hard was that just to say I'm
staying?
>> Uhhuh. I mean it kind of wasn't too hard
because like I was kind of a late uh
riser. So I had a few couple uh offers
but also seeing coach Mazine coming in.
He won a national championship. So it's
like you can't take that away from him.
And he also beat Nick Sabin.
Says that all the time.
Good idea.
>> So yeah. So yeah, it really didn't come
to my mind.
>> That good. Okay.
>> Let's uh take some photos.
>> Yeah.
>> See you come up here and get a shot with
us.
Jersey.
>> Never know which camera.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Ready?
>> One, two, three.
>> Okay. right here.
>> Yeah.
All right. One, two, three.
These are a little creepy. Melt.